英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with Day 9 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Soresi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今日木曜日は今週練習した表現を実際の会話で使えるようにトレーニングしてきます。
Okay, let's get started.
Express.
Create.
Reply.
まずはウォーミングアップをしましょう。
Step 1. Express.
今からジェニーさんが今週練習した表現をランダムに言ってくれますので、
何も見ないで全部リピートできるかチャレンジしてみてください。
So try to say it quickly and smoothly.
And copy my intonation.
Okay, here we go.
Am I overdressed?
I'd like to rent a kilt.
Is it for a special occasion?
This hat might look good on you.
I don't look good in hats.
How does it feel?
It feels nice.
All right. Did you express all those phrases quickly and smoothly?
And now, let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Create.
続いては、今週練習したフレーズを使ってオリジナルの英文を作ってみましょう。
まずはこちら。
この〜は私に似合っていますか?
Does this〜 look good on me?
このフレーズを使って服や身につけているものについて
似合っているか尋ねましょう
Are you ready?
Does this...
どうぞ
文を作れましたか?
では、ジェニーさんならどんな文を作るか聞きましょう
ジェニー
Does this sweater look good on me?
それでは同じフレーズを使ってもう一度文を作ってみましょう。
Now try to create one more original sentence.
いきますよ。
Does this...
どうぞ。
それでは二つ目のフレーズ。
その何々はすごく似合っていますよ。
さあ、クリエイトしましょう。
行きますよ。
どうぞ。
OK, Jenny, it's your turn.
みなさん、どんな文を作りましたか?
それでは、もう一度、
that 〜 looks great on you の文を作りましょう。
どうぞ。
OK, let's go to the next one.
三つ目のクリエイト。
〜を試着してもいいですか?
Is it OK if I try on 〜?
ショッピングしていることを想像して、試着してもいいか尋ねましょう。
Is it okay if I try on...
どうぞ。
All right, let's see what Jenny would like to try on.
Is it okay if I try on these shoes?
わかりましたか?
These shoes.
複数形で表現します。
Is it okay if I try on these shoes?
それでは皆さん、もう一度文を作りましょう。
Is it okay if I try on...
どうぞ。
Okay, now let's move on to our final step.
Step 3. Reply.
では、さらに実践的なトレーニングをします。
英語の問いかけに対して、英語で自由に返答しましょう。
まず一つ目、想像してください。
店員さんに洋服選びを手伝ってもらっています。
そこでこのように聞かれます。
How tall are you?
身長どれくらいあるか、数字だけではなく、文の形で分かりやすく答えましょう。
いきますよ。
How tall are you?
どうぞ。
それでは、返答例を聞きましょう。
How tall are you?
In centimeters, I'm 170 centimeters tall.
I'm not sure how many inches that is.
センチメートルとインチの測り方がありますね。
それを配慮して、先にin centimeters, I'm,
そして数字、centimeters tall。
そして補足文として、
I'm not sure how many inches that is.
今週練習しましたね。
それでは、もう一度質問しますよ。
How tall are you?
さて、二つ目のクエスチョンに行きましょう。
店員さんに普段着る服のサイズを聞かれます。
Are your clothes usually a large, medium, or small?
medium, small, na do, size dake de iu no de wa naku, bun no katachi de kotaimashou.
Are you ready?
Are your clothes usually a large, medium, or small?
Dozo.
Dewa, hentou rei desu.
Are your clothes usually a large, medium, or small?
Usually, I wear a large for t-shirts or dress shirts.
具体的な洋服に関して答えましたね。
Usually, I wear a large そしてその後 for t-shirts あるいはワイシャツ or dress shirts.
OK, let's try this one more time.
I'll ask the question and you answer in your own words.
Are your clothes usually a large, medium or small?
それでは最後の問いかけです あなたは服を試着しました
店員さんから着心地はどうか聞かれます
How does it feel? Too tight? Too loose?
自分なりに答えるためにまずどういった服を試着しているか自由に想像してください
では行きますよ
How does it feel? Too tight? Too loose?
どうぞ
By the way, Jenny, what kind of clothes are you trying on?
I'm trying on a shirt.
それでは、シャツを試着していることを想像して答えてもらいましょう。
How does it feel? Too tight? Too loose?
It feels a little loose, but not too loose. Maybe it's just right.
わかりましたか? It feels a little loose.
でもゆるすぎではありません。
But not too loose.
ではみなさん、もう一度同じ問いかけをしますので、答えてみてください。
いきますよ。
How does it feel?
Too tight? Too loose?
Okay, time's up.
Great job today, everyone.
さて、明日は対話カラオケです。
あなたはスコットランドの伝統衣装をレンタルする場面で会話をします。
身長や普段着る服のサイズなどを聞かれますので、
今週練習した表現を使って店員さんに上手に伝えてみてくださいね。
So you'll try to complete the conversation in your own words.
You can do it!
So everyone, get on board!
And let's practice speaking together!
See you next time on Ekaima Time Trial.
Bye-bye.